<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>


<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<link>http://www.ufc.com</link>
		<title>UFC</title>
		<description></description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 23:51:33 EST</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 23:51:33 EST</lastBuildDate>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[The Big Payback – Penn gets Even with Pulver; Diaz Takes TUF5 Title]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6532</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6532</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - It took five years, but tonight at The Pearl at The Palms Hotel, BJ Penn erased the most discouraging loss of his career in punishing style, submitting Jens Pulver in the second round to break a two fight losing streak and begin the next phase of his career with a bruising exclamation point.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 03:01:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Ufc In The News</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[The Ultimate Fighter 5 Finale - Weigh-In Results]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6519</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6519</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Click below for the official weigh-in results for Saturday's finale of The Ultimate Fighter, season five.  The card will air on Spike TV from The Palms in Las Vegas at 9pm on Saturday, June 23rd.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 02:59:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Ufc In The News</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Andy Wang - Pursuing Perfection]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6500</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6500</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - For many of the fighters competing in the Ultimate Fighter 5 finale this Saturday night in Las Vegas, it's more than just a payday and a chance to put another win on their records.   For those making their Octagon debuts, it's an opportunity to establish themselves in the MMA world and also let their families in on the celebration as they finally make it to the big show.But Andy Wang, who faces fellow TUF5 castmate Cole Miller, won't have his entire family in attendance.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 18:32:01 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Interview</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Pulver Goes for Two in a Row over Penn]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6488</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6488</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - A lot can change in five years, especially in the world of mixed martial arts, but despite contract issues, impressive wins, and devastating losses, Jens Pulver remains standing. It's an unlikely destination for a life and career that has been anything but smooth sailing, but it's also the end result of what determination and heart can do in any walk of life.  So if you see Pulver around The Palms in Las Vegas in the days before his Saturday main event against old rival BJ Penn, and he's smiling, you'll know why.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2007 12:12:01 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Interview</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Gamburyan’s Relentless Charge leads him to Vegas Saturday]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6485</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6485</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - Entering season five of The Ultimate Fighter reality show, most believed that at best, Manvel 'Manny' Gamburyan would possibly do enough to warrant an undercard bout on the season finale card, but nothing more.  Few but the hardcore fans knew who he was, and at 5 foot 5, they figured that he was just too small to compete against the young guns of the 155-pound weight class.Two believed though - Gamburyan, and his coach, Jens Pulver.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2007 23:05:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Interview</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Maynard Eager to 'Bully' the 155 Pound Division]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6467</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6467</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - Gray Maynard thought he was done when it came to competitive athletics.  A three-time All-American wrestler for Michigan State, Maynard had fallen short of his dream of making the 2004 Olympic team, and after years of sacrifice, he was tired of the 'other' stuff that went along with being a top-flight wrestler, such as weight cutting.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 23:25:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Interview</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Penn’s Got Five Years worth of Payback on His Mind]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6458</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6458</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - The morning after.  It's when the adrenaline dies down and when reality sets in.  On the morning of January 12, 2002, BJ Penn didn't like how his world had changed in the previous 12 hours.  After losing a five round majority decision to Jens Pulver the night before, he knew what it was like to be on the other side, and not only didn't he like it, it threw his world into upheaval.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 12:44:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Interview</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Diaz Doing the Family Name Proud]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6445</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6445</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - Hours and hours of torturous training, dealing with various aches and pains in muscles you didn't even know existed, pre-fight tension so thick you could cut it with a knife, and then 15 minutes of war with an adversary who has been training to either knock your head into the third row or to twist your arm or leg in directions it was never intended to go in.Being a professional fighter is no joke.  But for Nathan Diaz, fighting isn't just the only thing he knows, it's the only thing he could ever picture himself doing.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 20:32:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Interview</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Who’s Now? It’s got to be 'The Natural']]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6420</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6420</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - What makes an Ultimate Sports Star?  That's what ESPN is attempting to find out this summer when it puts together 32 professional athletes from fan nominations, groups them in brackets, NCAA tournament style, and then eliminates them, matchup by matchup, until a winner is crowned.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2007 12:05:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Ufc In The News</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Franklin and Forrest Outlast Foes at UFC 72]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6421</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=6421</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Thomas Gerbasi, UFC - Former UFC Middleweight Champion Rich Franklin survived some dicey moments in the final round of his bout against Yushin Okami tonight at the Odyssey Arena, but in the end, 'Ace' had put in enough early work to earn a unanimous decision in the UFC 72 main event and another shot at the 185-pound title he lost in October of 2006.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2007 20:30:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Ufc In The News</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[ZUFFA, LLC NAMES MICHAEL PINE VICE PRESIDENT OF THE UFC]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5951</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5951</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Las Vegas, NV (USA) - The Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; (UFC&reg;) organization today announced that Turner Broadcasting veteran Michael Pine has joined Zuffa, LLC to become Vice President of Ad Sales and Sponsorships.  In this position, Pine will manage and oversee all operations of the advertising and sponsorship business for the Las Vegas-based Ultimate Fighting Championship.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2007 01:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[ESPNEWS TO BROADCAST UFC 71 WEIGH-INS]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5893</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5893</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Las Vegas, Nev. (USA) - On Friday, May 25, beginning at 4 pm PST (7 p.m. EST), ESPNEWS, the nation's only 24-hour sports news television network, will present live coverage of the weigh-ins for UFC 71: LIDDELL vs. JACKSON featuring UFC World Light Heavyweight Champion Chuck "The Iceman" Liddell vs. Quinton "Rampage" Jackson from the MGM Grand Garden Arena in Las Vegas.  This will mark the first time a major national sports television network will feature live event coverage of the UFC weigh-ins. ESPNEWS anchor David Lloyd will host the network's coverage from ESPN's Bristol, Conn. studios.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2007 17:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UFC Conquers the Worldwide Leader in Sports]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5783</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5783</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[UFC&reg; Light Heavyweight Champion Chuck "The Iceman" Liddell Becomes First Fighter in UFC History to Grace Cover of ESPN The Magazine
Las Vegas, NV (USA) - The unstoppable Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; (UFC&reg;) organization has won over yet another media giant - this time the "Worldwide Leader in Sports" - with the undeniable popularity and mass appeal of its brand of mixed martial arts.  UFC World Light Heavyweight Champion Chuck "The Iceman" Liddell, who shows his softer side along with his eight-year old son, Cade, both grace the current issue of ESPN the Magazine.  The issue, which marks the first time a UFC fighter has ever graced the cover, hits newsstands today.  The cover is timed to coincide with Chuck's upcoming battle vs. Quinton "Rampage" Jackson May 26th at the MGM Grand Garden Arena in Las Vegas.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 18:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[Stout-Fisher Rematch Headlines UFC Fight Night in Florida on June 12]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5764</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5764</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Las Vegas, NV (USA) - The Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; (UFC&reg;) organization brings its UFC&reg; Fight Night&trade; series of live events telecast on Spike TV back to Hollywood, Fla. for its third event at the Seminole Hard Rock Hotel &amp; Casino in Hard Rock Live.  Headlining the South Florida card is Spencer "The King" Fisher vs. Canada's Sam "Hands of Stone" Stout in a highly anticipated rematch of one of 2006's best lightweight bouts.  As a special feature, undefeated wrestling expert Jon Fitch will take on Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu specialist Roan Carneiro in a sizzling170-pound matchup.  UFC Fight Night will take place inside the Hard Rock Live and will telecast live on Spike TV Tuesday, June 12 starting at 9pm ET/PT (tape delay).]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 09:31:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[The World is Ready for the UFC - UFC 73 on July 7th]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5723</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5723</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Las Vegas, NV (USA) - Tired of paying your hard-earned cash for events packed with hype and little else? Sick of sitting down for a pay-per-view event and finding out that you're paying over $50 for just three fights that include a showcase and a mismatch? The Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; has the cure for what is ailing fight fans, and in a continuing effort to provide what the world is truly waiting for, it is announcing yet another UFC card stacked with at least five fights that include two intense championship bouts and a heated grudge match between two light heavyweight rivals.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 00:33:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UFC® Returns to The Pearl at The Palms for The Ultimate Fighter® 5 Finale]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5555</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5555</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Las Vegas, Nev. - April 24, 2007 - When former UFC&reg; Lightweight Champion Jens Pulver defeated the seemingly invincible BJ Penn in 2002, he shocked the world and proved that when it comes to the Octagon&trade;, nothing is impossible.  Since then, Penn has plotted his revenge and waited seemingly in vain for the opportunity to avenge his first and most bitter defeat. But on Saturday, June 23rd, these two 155-pound pioneers - who matched wits for six weeks as coaches on The Ultimate Fighter&reg; Season 5 - square off in a rematch five years in the making and finally get the chance to settle their score with their fists when they battle in the main event on The Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; organization and Spike TV's The Ultimate Fighter 5 Season finale live from The Pearl at The Palms in Las Vegas.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 18:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UFC 70: NATIONS COLLIDE RESULTS]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5516</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5516</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[MANCHESTER - For years, Mirko "Cro Cop" had knocked opponents out in devastating fashion with fearsome kicks to the head.  Tonight, before a packed house at the MEN Arena, Gabriel Gonzaga gave the Croatian bomber a taste of his own medicine, sending him crashing to defeat with a single right kick to the head in the Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; (UFC&reg;) organization's UFC 70: NATIONS COLLIDE main event, earning himself a shot at UFC Heavyweight Champion Randy Couture in the process.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 08:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[ANNOUNCES FIRST EVER FIGHT IN BELFAST]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5411</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5411</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[Manchester, England (UK) - The Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; (UFC&reg;) organization today announced it will bring the world's most exciting mixed martial arts event straight back to Europe, this time to fight fans in Northern Ireland.  Topping off the international lineup of fights will be the middleweight main event clash Rich "Ace" Franklin vs. Denmark's Martin Kampmann, and the light heavyweight special feature Forrest Griffin vs. Hector Ramirez.  UFC 72: VICTORY will take place live from Belfast at the Odyssey Arena Saturday, June 16, 2007.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 16:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UFC 69: SHOOTOUT RESULTS]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5341</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5341</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[SATURDAY, APRIL 7LIVE FROM TOYOTA CENTER IN HOUSTON
Houston, TX - Odds mean nothing.  The past means nothing.  In mixed martial arts, what matters is what happens when the bell rings.  And when the bell rang at Toyota Center tonight, Matt Serra came to fight.  When you do that, good things can happen, and they did for the Long Island native, who stunned the mixed martial arts world with a first round TKO win over Georges St-Pierre to win the Welterweight Championship in the Ultimate Fighting Championship&reg; (UFC&reg;) organization's UFC 69: SHOOTOUT main event.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 03:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title><![CDATA[UFC® Fight Night™ Live from The Pearl Results]]></title>
			
	        
			
			<link>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5343</link>
			<guid>http://www.ufc.com/index.cfm?fa=news.detail&amp;gid=5343</guid>
			
			<description><![CDATA[UFC&reg; Fight Night&trade; Live from The Pearl Results   Stevenson Makes Quick Work of GuillardMcCully Decisions Hardonk; Florian Submits Mishima
Las Vegas, Nev. - April 5, 2007 -The bad blood was evident between lightweight contenders Joe Stevenson and Melvin Guillard leading up to their UFC&reg; Fight Night&trade; main event at The Pearl at The Palms tonight, but Stevenson was a cool customer once the bell rang, stunning all in attendance with a seemingly effortless 27 second submission win over "The Young Assassin."
"I was nervous with his athletic ability and explosiveness and it could have gone just as fast the other way," said the gracious Stevenson.]]></description>
			
			
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2007 03:00:00 EST</pubDate>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>








