<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780</id><updated>2007-05-21T15:51:35.859-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Official Google Blog</title><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/'></link><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25'></link><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'></link><author><name>Eric Case</name></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>500</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-3247118463291220566</id><published>2007-05-18T15:09:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-05-18T15:11:28.201-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Massage interviews?</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Reza Behforooz, Massage expert and Software Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Life at the Googleplex is often full of fun surprises. One day, I was asked if I could do a massage interview. I was already a big fan of our massage program, and I was familiar with doing interviews at Google, but I didn't know about massage interviews. Regardless, it sounded Googley, and I decided to help.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Getting a massage at work is a favorite &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/support/jobs/bin/static.py?page=benefits.html&amp;benefits=us#bbb"&gt;perk&lt;/a&gt; among Googlers. As with anyone we hire, our massage therapists have to go through an interview process...but the actual interviews are a little unique. We ask the therapists to do what they do best -- give massages. And as Googlers, it is our duty to help with the hard task of receiving table or chair massages as part the interviews. Though we do have to write detailed feedback about the massage, just like any other interview, in this interview, all I had to do was close my eyes and relax. Who knew interviewing could be so easy!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/05/massage-interviews.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3247118463291220566'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/3247118463291220566'></link><author><name>Molly Graham</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-856790870009222418</id><published>2007-05-18T08:42:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-05-18T08:41:20.166-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Google Apps Partner Edition</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Hunter Middleton, Product Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From the beginning, we envisioned making &lt;a href="http://google.com/a"&gt;Google Apps&lt;/a&gt; available to any organization that might want to offer this innovative set of services to its employees, customers, students, members, or any other associates of the organization. Today, we're excited to take another step in that direction by releasing a version of Google Apps specifically designed for ISPs, portals, and other service providers, whether you have a few thousand subscribers or over a million. This new version, which we're calling the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/a/help/intl/en/admins/partner_edition.html"&gt;Partner Edition&lt;/a&gt;, makes it easy for large and small service providers to offer your subscribers the latest versions of powerful tools, like Gmail, Google Calendar, and Google Docs &amp;amp; Spreadsheets, without having to worry about hosting, updating, or maintaining any of the services yourself. All you have to do is point and click in the easy admin control panel and figure out what branding you'd like to layer on top of the products in order to create a customized look and feel. You can quit spending your resources and time on applications like webmail -- and leave the work to our busy bees at the Googleplex.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/05/google-apps-partner-edition.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/856790870009222418'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/856790870009222418'></link><author><name>Molly Graham</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-4241271487609470858</id><published>2007-05-17T09:00:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-05-17T08:57:57.880-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Google Book Search becomes more comprehensive</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Adam Mathes, Product Manager, Book Search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://books.google.com/"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Google Book Search&lt;/a&gt; allows you to instantly search the full text of over a million digitized books, but we thought that wasn't quite enough. Now when you search you'll get both digitized book results as well as records for millions of other books that still just exist in the analog world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When you view these new added book records, you can often read reviews, a summary, or see what other people had to say about the book around the web. Since these books haven't been digitally indexed yet, you can't preview the text online, but if you've discovered something great, we offer links to buy the book or &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/08/finding-wealth-in-your-library-and.html"&gt;find it in a library near you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We're doing this because we want to offer users the most comprehensive book search in the world - whether it's a book you can &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=cyokAAAAMAAJ&amp;pg=PPA7"&gt;read online now&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=dO-sDl1ySHoC&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover"&gt;preview samples&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=HbwYAAAAMAAJ&amp;dq=paul+otlet&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;q=documentation&amp;amp;pgis=1"&gt;see a few snippets&lt;/a&gt;, or just read what &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?vid=ISBN0783556756"&gt;others have written&lt;/a&gt; about the book. We're still very busy digitizing millions more books, but want to make as much discoverable as possible today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To find out more, check out our post on &lt;a href="http://booksearch.blogspot.com/2007/05/found-more-books.html"&gt;Inside Google Book Search&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/05/google-book-search-becomes-more.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4241271487609470858'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/4241271487609470858'></link><author><name>Molly Graham</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-2848965407454350944</id><published>2007-05-17T07:55:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-05-17T07:54:56.719-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Oh, the places you'll go....</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Tammy McLeod, Software Engineer, Picasa Web Albums&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If all you ever wanted to do is direct, now's your chance. You can use our free photo sharing service, &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com"&gt;Picasa Web Albums&lt;/a&gt;, to create nifty portable Flash slideshows that you can easily embed in any blog or web page. Check out this slideshow of our new Hollywood-themed office in Santa Monica.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/bin/slideshow.swf" flashvars="host= picasaweb.google.com&amp;captions=1&amp;amp;RGB=0x000000&amp;amp;feed=http%3A%2F%2Fpicasaweb.google.com%2Fdata%2Ffeed%2Fapi%2Fuser%2Ftester%2Falbumid%2F5061951474333359457%3Fkind%3Dphoto%26alt%3Drss%26authkey%3D3V8IljiqEO0" pluginspage=" http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer" height="192" width="288"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The playback controls are built right in -- just roll over the slideshow to reveal them -- and it just takes a quick click for friends to get started on creating their own masterpiece.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/05/oh-places-youll-go.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2848965407454350944'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/2848965407454350944'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-5752554675924592282</id><published>2007-05-16T16:32:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-05-16T16:48:34.974-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Behind the scenes with universal search</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by David Bailey, Tech Lead, and Johanna Wright, Product Manager, universal search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So when we were asked to make the vision &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/05/universal-search-best-answer-is-still.html"&gt;Marissa describes&lt;/a&gt; about universal search into a reality, we admit we were a little daunted. Googlers had tried before to do this without success -- several times. Finding the best answer across multiple content types is a well-known hard problem in the search field. Besides that, we wondered if we had become too big a company to pull off a project this complex.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's the challenge in a nutshell: Until now, we've only been able to show news, books, local and other such results at the top of the page, like this example for [&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=trends+in+education+&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search"&gt;trends in education&lt;/a&gt;]. But it's a tall order to earn placement at the top of our search results, so plenty often we end up not showing these kinds of results even when they might be useful. If only we could smartly place such results elsewhere on the page when they don't quite deserve the top, we could share the benefits of these great Google features with people much more often.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One challenge was being able to regularly search through all of the additional content types to find relevant results. After all, you don't know if there might be a minor news story or an obscure book relevant to your query unless you go and check. But Google's massive compute cluster -- and much effort by our infrastructure experts -- gave us a leg up on that one, and we can now search these disparate types of information about as efficiently as we search our massive index of web pages. We may have melted down a data center or two along the way, but then bugs are part of life in this business!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next challenge was deciding when and where such results should blend in. Fortunately we have some of the world's experts on ranking, and have been able to apply the lessons learned on web search to ensure that we show news only for newsworthy queries, scanned books only when there aren't better web results, etc. It can be tricky. As we learned the hard way, just because everyone under the sun is writing about Anna Nicole Smith doesn't mean news about her should show up for the search [baby names].&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lastly, we faced the challenge of the user interface you see on the screen -- the UI. The new UI for these results is subtle, but this is one reason why the project is fun for our designers and usability experts: they get to focus on creating a simple experience for you. For example, with news results they designed a compact look for the result that includes helpful items like an image and a date, but is limited to just the most salient information. Or take our book search results, which call out the author and number of pages in the book. (Of course, we learned that sometimes you don't even need to design a user interface. In one early usability study, shortly after Barry Bonds broke Babe Ruth's home run record, we asked people "how many home runs has Barry Bonds hit?" hoping they would type [barry bonds] into the search box. Instead, each and every one simply blurted out "715".)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We also called on experts from each of our feature areas such as News and Local, and were delighted to find our startup mindset is alive and well.  Folks from all over found spare time and pitched in to get us to the finish line. There were many nights when we went to bed knowing that plenty of the team's IM status still reported they were online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And after all this elbow grease, finally we have something that works. What does it mean for you?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Although it's just a beginning, this first pass of universal search focuses on video, news, local and books. Now you'll be able to get more information Google knows about directly from within the search results. You won't have to know about specialized areas of content. If you're looking for the [&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=atkins+southwestern+pork+fajitas&amp;amp;btnG=Search"&gt;atkins southwestern pork fajitas&lt;/a&gt;] recipe, we can now link you right to that page in the book. Or if, like me, you've been busy these past few days and have not caught up with your Tivo, don't type [&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=sopranos&amp;amp;btnG=Search"&gt;sopranos&lt;/a&gt;] into Google, because our news result will be a giant spoiler. The search for [&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?aq=t&amp;oq=rachmaninoff+concerto+&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;q=rachmaninoff+concerto+3"&gt;rachmaninoff concerto 3&lt;/a&gt;] includes a video of Vladimir Horowitz performing this piece (scroll down to see it), and [&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=Animator+vs.+Animation+2&amp;amp;btnG=Search"&gt;Animator vs. Animation 2&lt;/a&gt;] is pretty cool as well. (And as Johanna notes: I was delighted to see that when querying for my son's name a video showed up too.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is just the tip of the iceberg in making Google results more comprehensive and useful. It has involved launching a number of new systems that will make it much easier for us to continue making improvements so you get the most relevant information from our varied content areas. We hope you like it. And finally, we're especially happy to know that Google is still very much a place where we can get big things done!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/05/behind-scenes-with-universal-search.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5752554675924592282'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/5752554675924592282'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-3778712785379083326</id><published>2007-05-16T16:19:00.000-07:00</published><updated>2007-05-16T16:19:52.798-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Universal search: The best answer is still the best answer</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Marissa Mayer, VP Search Products &amp; User Experience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Back in 2001, Eric asked for a brainstorm of a few "splashy" ideas in search. A designer and product manager at the time, I made a few mockups -- one of which was for 'universal search.' It was a sample search results page for Britney Spears that, in addition to web results, also had news, images, and groups results right on the same page. Even then, we could see that people could easily become overwhelmed with the number of different search tools available on Google -- let alone those that would be created over the next few years. This proliferation of tools, while useful, has outgrown the old model of search. We want to help you find the very best answer, even if you don't know where to look.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That mockup and early observations were the motivation behind the universal search effort we announced earlier today. And while that Britney Spears mockup was the start of Google's universal search vision, it was instantly obvious that this would be one of the biggest architectural, ranking, and interface challenges we would face at Google. Over several years, with the help of more than 100 people, we've built the infrastructure, search algorithms, and presentation mechanisms to provide what we see as just the first step in the evolution toward universal search. Today, we're making that first step available on google.com by launching the new architecture and using it to blend content from Images, Maps, Books, Video, and News into our web results.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With universal search, we're attempting to break down the walls that traditionally separated our various search properties and integrate the vast amounts of information available into one simple set of search results.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here are a few of my favorite searches that show off the power of universal search:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=+steve+jobs&amp;btnG=Search"&gt;steve jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=darth+vader&amp;btnG=Search"&gt;darth vader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=nosferatu&amp;btnG=Search"&gt;nosferatu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;In addition, we've rolled out a few new navigation elements and experimental features to help our users better navigate our site and find the information they're looking for. These include contextual navigation links above the search results that help users "drill down" to specific types of information. For instance, developers who search for [&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=python&amp;btnG=Search"&gt;python&lt;/a&gt;] will see links for "web," "blogs," "books," "groups," and "code," whereas [&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=downtown+los+angeles&amp;amp;btnG=Search"&gt;downtown los angeles&lt;/a&gt;] will show a different set of links. Also, in terms of integration and navigation, today we introduced a new universal navigation bar at the top of all Google web pages to provide easier navigation to your favorite Google products, such as Gmail.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While today's releases are big steps in making the world's information more easily accessible, these are just the beginning steps toward the universal search vision.  Stay tuned!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/05/universal-search-best-answer-is-still.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3778712785379083326'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/3778712785379083326'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116598032581424721</id><published>2006-12-14T09:55:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:53:17.355-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Holiday goodies from Picasa Web Albums</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Adrian Graham, Product Manager, Picasa&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What’s a holiday without the memorable (and embarrassing) photos? The holidays are almost here, which (at least if you’re in my family) means babies chewing on presents, the dog dressed in a ridiculous reindeer costume, and someone (cough, Uncle Charlie) passed out after too much eggnog. Although I think about this now and wince in advance, I know that I’m going to want to capture these moments and more importantly, share them with the rest of my family and friends. That’s why I’m excited about the new features we’ve added to Picasa Web Albums, just in time for the holidays.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Print ordering is my favorite—it’s something you have told us you've wanted since we first launched. Now, when you or anyone else views photos in &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com"&gt;Picasa Web Albums&lt;/a&gt;, there’s an option to order prints directly from the site. We currently offer prints and products from Shutterfly and PhotoWorks, but we’ll be adding more soon. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other new features include video upload for easy sharing (it’s just like with photos—select them in Picasa and click the “Web Album” button) and searching tools. Now you can search over your own captions, album titles, and album descriptions, and you can even search for photos in your friends’ public albums. Digging up that picture of me trying to figure out which end of the holiday turkey is "up" should be easier than ever. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So &lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/tester/SampleAlbum/photo#5008248582488977682"&gt;check out these new features&lt;/a&gt; before all the festivities start. And however you celebrate the holidays this year, I hope you’ll take lots of pictures.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/12/holiday-goodies-from-picasa-web-albums_14.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116598032581424721'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116598032581424721'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116586485547650908</id><published>2006-12-13T17:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:53:11.477-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Now you can search for U.S. patents</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Doug Banks, Software Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We've all heard about the Wright brothers, Thomas Edison, and Alexander Graham Bell -- famous inventors whose creative minds changed the course of history. But there are many more like them, and millions of inventions that have been patented in the U.S. alone -- from useful everyday items such as &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/patents?vid=USPATRE19128&amp;id=ZBMoAAAAEBAJ&amp;amp;printsec=abstract&amp;zoom=4#PPP1,M1"&gt;adhesive tape&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/patents?vid=USPAT2196066&amp;amp;id=EvtGAAAAEBAJ&amp;pg=PP1"&gt;contact lenses&lt;/a&gt; to, er, things useful in specific situations, like this &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/patents?vid=USPAT4833729&amp;amp;id=KBE3AAAAEBAJ&amp;pg=RA1-PA4-IA1"&gt;shark protector suit&lt;/a&gt; or this &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/patents?vid=USPAT4076251&amp;amp;id=N-c5AAAAEBAJ&amp;printsec=abstract&amp;amp;zoom=4#PPA2,M1"&gt;amusement device incorporating simulated cheese and mice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today, we're excited to be releasing the beta version of &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/patents"&gt;Google Patent Search&lt;/a&gt;, which makes it easy to search the full text of the U.S. patent corpus and find patents that interest you. Start your exploration at &lt;b&gt;www.google.com/patents&lt;/b&gt; or visit the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/advanced_patent_search"&gt;Advanced Patent Search page&lt;/a&gt; to search by criteria, including patent number, inventor, and filing date. You can view images of original patents online.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Google Patent Search uses much of the same technology that powers &lt;a href="http://books.google.com"&gt;Google Book Search&lt;/a&gt;, so you can &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/11/new-way-to-browse-books.html"&gt;scroll through pages and zoom in&lt;/a&gt; on text and illustrations just like you can with books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's a natural extension of our mission to make this public domain government information more easily accessible using Google’s search technology. We’re pleased to have started with over 7 million patents granted by the &lt;a href="http://www.uspto.gov/"&gt;United States Patent and Trademark Office&lt;/a&gt; (USPTO) and look forward to expanding our coverage over time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold; font-style: italic;"&gt;Update:&lt;/span&gt; Removed mention of saving and printing as we're still working on that.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/12/now-you-can-search-for-us-patents.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116586485547650908'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116586485547650908'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-4238402800293036192</id><published>2007-01-09T06:03:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:52:36.391-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Super models wanted</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by John Hanke, Director, Google Earth &amp; Maps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That’s right, Google is looking for the hottest models on the planet. They can come from any city in the world, and they can be any height, but they must be interesting to look at, well-made and lightweight.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, by "lightweight" we mean that the file size should be reasonably small.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’re confused, you may not have heard about the recent updates of Google Earth, Google SketchUp, and the 3D Warehouse. With these launches, all the pieces are now in place for contributors to the 3D Warehouse to see their creations show up in Google Earth for all the world to see.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;br /&gt;1. Download &lt;a href="http://sketchup.google.com"&gt;Google SketchUp&lt;/a&gt;. Create a 3D model of something in your neighborhood, city or state -- your house, your business, your favorite restaurant, or the statue of Buckminster Fuller in the center of town. Be sure to geo-locate your model in Google Earth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2. Upload your model to the &lt;a href="http://sketchup.google.com/3dwarehouse/"&gt;3D Warehouse&lt;/a&gt;. Don’t forget to put your name on it (if it shows up in Google Earth, you’ll want the credit).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3. Download the most recent version of &lt;a href="http://earth.google.com"&gt;Google Earth&lt;/a&gt; (a necessary step, as older versions don’t support super models). Launch Google Earth, go to the 3D Buildings folder under the Layers tab in the lefthand sidebar, and activate the “Best of 3D Warehouse.” Then fly to the location of the model you submitted. It might be there!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you don’t find it, keep checking -- sometimes it takes several weeks for models to appear in Google Earth. In the meantime, visit “Best of 3D Warehouse” to see some that have made the cut. (&lt;a href="http://sketchup.google.com/support/bin/answer.py?answer=57057&amp;hl=en"&gt;Here are the guidelines for building "super" models&lt;/a&gt;.) Fly to Denver CO, Boulder CO, New York, NY and Calgary, Canada to start. Then investigate other cities to see if they contain 3D buildings yet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In short, 3D modelers, Google Earth is your palette; Google SketchUp is your brush. Show the world what you've got!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Update&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Added a short list of cities already featuring "best of" models.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/01/super-models-wanted.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4238402800293036192'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/4238402800293036192'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116598083353895988</id><published>2006-12-12T20:29:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:52:30.086-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Nifty Toolbar upgrades for Firefox</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Annie Sullivan, Software Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ever since the latest version of the Google Toolbar for IE came out, Firefox users have been asking when they'll see the same new features in their favorite browser. Well, we've been hard at work on a new version of the Toolbar for Firefox -- &lt;a title="Google Toolbar 3 Beta" href="http://tools.google.com/firefox/toolbar/FT3/intl/en/"&gt;Google Toolbar 3 Beta&lt;/a&gt;  -- that lets you access your bookmarks from any computer, add custom buttons to your Toolbar, and share web pages via Blogger, Gmail, and SMS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In addition to adding all the features from the Google Toolbar for IE, there's another one just for Firefox users. When I surf the web, I want to be able to look at all the files I come across right in my browser. But a lot of times, I have to download files and view them with a separate application instead. Since &lt;a href="http://docs.google.com/"&gt;Google Docs &amp;amp; Spreadsheets&lt;/a&gt; launched, I've been able to look at those files right in my browser. Except the process is kind of clunky right now: I have to right-click on a link, download the file to my machine, and then upload it to Google Docs &amp;amp; Spreadsheets. I want to be able to just click on a link to a document or spreadsheet and have it show up in my browser. So I added a feature to the Google Toolbar for Firefox to do that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now you can surf the web a little bit faster. I hope you enjoy this feature as much as I do!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/12/nifty-toolbar-upgrades-for-firefox_12.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116598083353895988'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116598083353895988'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116630570224671407</id><published>2006-12-18T06:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:52:17.827-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Mapping Europe</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by John Hanke, Director, Google Earth &amp; Maps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As part of our ongoing effort to connect people to information about the world -- or perhaps le monde, die welt, el mundo -- around them, I'm pleased to tell you about the addition of a new team to Google. Today we acquired &lt;a href="http://www.Endoxon.com"&gt;Endoxon&lt;/a&gt;, an Internet mapping solutions company based in Lucerne, Switzerland.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Endoxon team has demonstrated passion and innovation in online mapping and has developed compelling technology that will enhance our Google geo products worldwide.  We're also excited about having a dedicated team in Europe that can bring a distinctively European focus to our Maps products in those markets.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/12/mapping-europe.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116630570224671407'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116630570224671407'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116648186128925254</id><published>2006-12-26T08:31:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:52:17.825-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Speech-friendly textual directions from Google Maps</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by T.V. Raman, Research Scientist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;From time to time, our own &lt;a href="http://emacspeak.sourceforge.net/raman/"&gt;T.V. Raman&lt;/a&gt; shares his tips on how to use Google from his perspective as a technologist who cannot see -- tips that sighted people, among others, may also find useful. - Ed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Google Maps and its associated local search is a quick and easy means of locating businesses and obtaining directions. Most people who use it already seem to enjoy the graphical interface with its extremely reactive GUI. But when using spoken output, this visual richness can get in the way of quickly listening to the results of a maps query.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As an alternative, Google Maps also provides a simple to use a textual interface that serves up directions very efficiently when working with a screenreader or a Braille display. This alternative view into Google Maps is here, at the &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/?output=html"&gt;Textual Maps UI&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;http://maps.google.com/?output=html&lt;/span&gt;). It's extremely useful for blind and visually impaired users, as well as an effective solution for those times when you're at a non-graphical display and need to quickly look up a location.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just type a simple English query of the form &lt;b&gt;start address to end address&lt;/b&gt; and quickly get the information you're looking for. Though we added this option to enhance the accessibility of Google Maps for blind and low-vision users, perhaps others will find this alternative view a useful addition to their maps arsenal.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/12/speech-friendly-textual-directions.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116648186128925254'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116648186128925254'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-3275377630388569554</id><published>2007-01-11T21:16:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:52:11.478-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Real-time quotes for free</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Katie Jacobs Stanton, Group Product Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At Google, we get excited about making all kinds of information accessible to  everyone. The more up-to-date the information, the more valuable it is. This is  particularly true in the world of finance; information, and timing of that  information, is money. Today, real-time quotes are not freely and easily available on the web. Some websites offer one real-time quote at a time, but typically only after you have enrolled in a service and/or signed a complicated legal agreement. Other sites approach the problem differently and show you streaming &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;delayed&lt;/span&gt; data, but that doesn't solve the problem either -- it masks it. What's  really important is getting free, easy and fast access to real-time quotes so you know how the market or your company is doing now, not as of twenty minutes ago.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a result, we've worked with the &lt;a href="http://sec.gov/"&gt;SEC&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://www.nyse.com/"&gt;New York Stock  Exchange&lt;/a&gt; (NYSE) and our D.C. trade association, &lt;a href="http://www.netcoalition.com/"&gt;NetCoalition&lt;/a&gt;, to find a way to bring stock data to Google users in a way that benefits users and is practical for all parties. &lt;a href="http://www.netcoalition.com/vertical/Sites/%7BF1D948CC-5797-482E-B502-743C873E2848%7D/uploads/%7B2DE79A1C-7CFE-4DD8-BE12-EAEF3CE234C6%7D.PDF"&gt;We have encouraged the SEC&lt;/a&gt; to ensure that this data can be made available to our users at fair and reasonable rates, and applaud their &lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/markets/economy/feeds/ap/2007/01/03/ap3296574.html"&gt;recent efforts&lt;/a&gt; to review this issue. Today, the NYSE has moved the issue a great step  forward with a &lt;a href="http://apps.nyse.com/commdata/pub19b4.nsf/rulefilings"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt; to the SEC which if approved, would allow you to see real-time, last-sale prices across all Google properties including &lt;a href="http://finance.google.com/"&gt;Google Finance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/ig/directory?url=http://www.google.com/ig/modules/finance_portfolios.xml"&gt;Personalized Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/mobile/"&gt;Mobile&lt;/a&gt;, and of course, &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?sourceid=navclient-ff&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;rls=GGGL,GGGL:2006-14,GGGL:en&amp;q=goog"&gt;Google.com&lt;/a&gt;. It won't matter if you're on Wall Street or Main Street -- you'll have free, easy and fast access to real-time prices from NYSE on Google.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So stay tuned on our progress with this. We're excited that financial data as we know it is about to change. In the meantime, &lt;a href="http://finance.google.com/finance/portfolio?action=view&amp;amp;pid=2"&gt;set up your portfolio&lt;/a&gt; on Google Finance today.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/01/real-time-quotes-for-free.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3275377630388569554'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/3275377630388569554'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116563204158245716</id><published>2006-12-23T08:26:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:52:05.511-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Where on Earth is Santa?</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Melissa Crounse, Chief Elf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you know, every Christmas Eve Santa Claus gets busy on his tricked-out sleigh, soaring around the globe to deliver presents to (presumably deserving) children the world over. This year, even if you don't have a reindeer team of your own, you can use the &lt;a href="http://earth.google.com/santa/"&gt;Google Earth Santa Tracker&lt;/a&gt; (That's &lt;a href="http://earth.google.com/santa/"&gt;earth.google.com/santa&lt;/a&gt;.) Follow along on every step of Santa's travels with Donner, Blitzen, and of course Rudolph, in all their 3-D satellite glory. And to all a good flight -- er, night!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/12/where-on-earth-is-santa.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116563204158245716'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116563204158245716'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116317532493979596</id><published>2006-11-10T09:29:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:51:59.112-07:00</updated><title type='text'>It's all about location</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Ethan Russell, Product Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We've had lots of &lt;a href="http://base.google.com/base/testimonials.html"&gt;success&lt;/a&gt; working with the real estate industry to make home listings more easily discoverable on Google. And we're constantly attending real estate industry events and working daily with partners to help connect them with potential home buyers by adding more and more of their listings to Google web search. Over and over again, we hear from you: keep it free and keep it simple and keep it free.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So today, on our first day at the &lt;a href="http://www.realtor.org/convhome.nsf/pages/confhome?OpenDocument"&gt;NAR event in New Orleans&lt;/a&gt;, we're happy to let you know that we've further simplified the process for real estate providers looking to &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/base/search?ui=g&amp;a_n0=housing&amp;amp;a_y0=9&amp;a_n0=housing&amp;amp;a_y0=9&amp;a_o0=&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;hl=en&amp;amp;nd=&amp;showrefine=0&amp;amp;q=&amp;btnG=Search+Housing&amp;amp;a_n2=listing+type&amp;a_y2=1&amp;amp;a_o2=0&amp;a_v2=&amp;amp;a_v2=&amp;a_n363=property+type&amp;amp;a_y363=1&amp;a_o363=0&amp;amp;a_v363=&amp;a_v363=&amp;amp;sl=true&amp;a_n152=location&amp;amp;a_y152=6&amp;a_o152=0&amp;amp;a_t152=30&amp;a_v152=columbus%2C+oh&amp;amp;a_n303=price&amp;a_u303=usd&amp;amp;a_y303=8&amp;a_o303=4&amp;amp;a_v303=&amp;a_f303=&amp;amp;a_t303=&amp;a_n650=bedrooms&amp;amp;a_y650=2&amp;a_o650=4&amp;amp;a_v650=&amp;a_f650=&amp;amp;a_t650=&amp;scoring=aa_152&amp;amp;us=0"&gt;make listings searchable on Google&lt;/a&gt; (and it's free, of course). Regardless of what kind of real estate professional you are, now you can easily go to &lt;a href="http://base.google.com/base/help/realestate.html"&gt;one page&lt;/a&gt; to upload your listings to Google Base so that people can find them through Google. There are even dedicated pages for you --whether you're &lt;a href="http://base.google.com/base/broker.html"&gt;brokers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://services.google.com/inquiry/base_agents"&gt;agents&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://base.google.com/base/mls.html"&gt;MLS&lt;/a&gt; , or &lt;a href="http://base.google.com/base/idx.html"&gt;IDX vendors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you're tech-savvy, you can of course continue to send listings to &lt;a href="http://base.google.com/base/overview.html"&gt;Google Base&lt;/a&gt; yourself. But in any case we hope you find the many upload options available to you friendly and easy to use. If you're interested in Google and real estate, do check out all of the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/events/realestatetools/index.html"&gt;tools available to you&lt;/a&gt;. And if you happen to be in New Orleans this weekend, stop by our NAR booth.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/11/its-all-about-location.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116317532493979596'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116317532493979596'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-1373016700125078500</id><published>2007-01-17T19:00:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:51:53.538-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Don't miss your opportunity to be part of Google's first Code Jam Latin America!</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span chatdir="2"&gt;&lt;span chatindex="E5B429F5C89AE07E1"&gt;Berthier Ribeiro-Neto, Engineering Site Director&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_7ZYqYi4xigk/Ra7a2VoNj2I/AAAAAAAAAAc/5eS9r86_Esw/s1600-h/CodeJam_LatAm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer;" src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_7ZYqYi4xigk/Ra7a2VoNj2I/AAAAAAAAAAc/5eS9r86_Esw/s320/CodeJam_LatAm.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5021191261618278242" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;There are only 5 days left until registration closes for &lt;span name="st"&gt; Google &lt;/span&gt; Code Jam Latin America 2007. So far over 4,000 competitors have signed up for a chance to showcase their programming skills and win an all expenses paid trip to &lt;span name="st"&gt;Google&lt;/span&gt;'s Brazil engineering office, where they will compete for R$75,000 (Brazilian reales) in cash and prizes. The finals will be held on March 1. Latin Americans have registered in large numbers from Brazil, Argentina, Mexico, Peru, Colombia, Chile, Venezuela and Ecuador as well as many other countries.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The top 50 finalists will be flown to Belo Horizonte to show us what they've got. Think you've got what it takes to Code Jam?  Click &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/codejamlatinamerica/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to register!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/01/dont-miss-your-opportunity-to-be-part.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/1373016700125078500'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/1373016700125078500'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-116733870112671732</id><published>2006-12-28T16:01:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:47:45.801-07:00</updated><title type='text'>How we came up with year-end Zeitgeist data</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Artem Boytsov, Software Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/zeitgeist.html"&gt;Zeitgeist&lt;/a&gt; is "the spirit of time." This is why when we come up with the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/zeitgeist2006.html"&gt;lists of top searches on Google.com for 2006&lt;/a&gt;, we do not simply retrieve the most frequently-searched terms for the period -- the truth is, they don't change that much from year to year. This list would be predominated by very generic searches, such as "ebay", "dictionary", "yellow pages," "games," "maps" -- and of course, a number of X-rated keywords. These are constants, and although unquestionably popular, we don't think they actually define the Zeitgeist.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Instead, we looked for those searches that were very popular in 2006 but were not as popular in 2005 -- the explosive queries, the topics that everyone obsessed over. To come up with this list, we looked at several thousand of 2006's most popular searches, and ranked them based on how much their popularity increased compared to 2005. ("Bebo", for example, had very little traffic in 2005.) We also gave a bit higher score to searches with more traffic. Similarly, our "what is" and "who is" lists are not necessarily the absolute most frequent searches, but rather those that best represent the passing year.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A final note: there was some confusion over the use of descriptors like "most popular" and "fastest-gaining" in &lt;a href="http://www.techmeme.com/061219/p49#a061219p49"&gt;media reports&lt;/a&gt; about our Zeitgeist. We've edited the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/zeitgeist2006.html"&gt;2006 Year-End Zeitgeist&lt;/a&gt; description to be more accurate on this point: "we compared frequent queries this year against 2005 to see what sorts of things were top of mind."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We hope you enjoyed our year-end Zeitgeist as much as we enjoyed working on it!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/12/how-we-came-up-with-year-end-zeitgeist.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/116733870112671732'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/116733870112671732'></link><author><name>A Googler</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-6522411072004968377</id><published>2007-02-20T13:54:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:53.598-07:00</updated><title type='text'>This is National Engineers Week</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Shannon Madison, Instructional Designer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's that time of year: to &lt;a href="http://www.eweek.org/"&gt;celebrate the engineers&lt;/a&gt;  who create the new technologies that revolutionize our world. Their work changes the way we work, play, learn, and communicate with each  other.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As part of our ongoing commitment to raise awareness of  these contributions (here's more on our &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/support/jobs/bin/answer.py?answer=57415"&gt;our K-12 initiatives&lt;/a&gt;), and to get young students interested in engineering, we're hosting a &lt;a href="http://www.eweek.org/2002/News/Eweek/girlsday.shtml"&gt;Introduce a Girl to Engineering Day&lt;/a&gt; on February 22nd in  several of our U.S. offices, including New York, Kirkland, and our headquarters in Mountain View. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hundreds of middle-school girls will come to these offices this week to buddy up with an engineer, attend interactive  workshops, take a tour, and, of course, have lunch. (Just like last year - see photo.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Ap14FtNN91w/RdttEo4wxWI/AAAAAAAAACs/WnqLMaYJmaw/s1600-h/Girls_Eng_day.jpg"&gt;&lt;img style="cursor: pointer;" src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Ap14FtNN91w/RdttEo4wxWI/AAAAAAAAACs/WnqLMaYJmaw/s320/Girls_Eng_day.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5033736934979061090" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's hoping the day will spark the interest of these young women to learn more about science, math and  engineering -- and maybe even inspire them to pursue engineering studies, so that they too can change our lives. Here's &lt;a href="http://www.eweek.org/site/Students/index.shtml"&gt;more for students&lt;/a&gt; to do, and &lt;a href="http://www.eweek.org/site/Teachers/index.shtml"&gt;a page for teachers&lt;/a&gt; too.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/02/this-is-national-engineers-week.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/6522411072004968377'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/6522411072004968377'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-6401948742646203427</id><published>2007-02-13T12:06:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:47.708-07:00</updated><title type='text'>About the Copiepresse decision</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Rachel Whetstone, European Director of Communications and Public Affairs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today we heard that the Belgian court, which last year ruled against us in the Copiepresse case has reaffirmed its original decision.  This judgment is clearly disappointing, and we intend to appeal it because we believe that Google.be and Google News are entirely legal and provide great value and critical information to Internet users. However, we are very pleased that the judge agreed Google should be given notice of articles and other material that content owners want removed. As we have in the past, we will honor all requests to remove such materials.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is important to remember that both Google Web Search and Google News only ever show a few snippets of text. If people want to read the entire story they have to click through to the web publisher's site where the information resides.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's a quick summary of the case: Copiepresse represents a number of newspapers in Belgium. It sued Google last August claiming that our search engine and news site breached these publications' copyright. &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/09/about-google-news-case-in-belgium.html"&gt;In September&lt;/a&gt;, the court ruled in favor of Copiepresse, ordering us to remove these publishers' content from both Google.be and Google News. We complied with that order and also posted the ruling to both home pages.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today's ruling does not affect the current content of Google News because the websites represented by Copiepresse have already been removed from Google News. In fact, hundreds of news publishers in Belgium and around the world are delighted to be included in Google News because it helps more people find their websites and read their articles. That's why Google receives far more requests for inclusion than requests for removal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We believe search engines are of real benefit to publishers because they drive valuable traffic to their websites. If publishers do not want their websites to appear in search results, &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/01/controlling-how-search-engines-access.html"&gt;technical standards like robots.txt and metatags&lt;/a&gt; enable them automatically to prevent the indexation of their content. These Internet standards are nearly universally accepted and are honored by all reputable search engines. In addition, Google has a clear policy of respecting the wishes of content owners. If a newspaper does not want to be part of Google News, we remove their content from our index—all the newspaper has to do is ask. There is no need for legal action and all the associated costs.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/02/about-copiepresse-decision.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/6401948742646203427'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/6401948742646203427'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-8279978029017418739</id><published>2007-02-05T12:05:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:38.642-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Google Maps down under</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Noel Gordon, Software Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many Australians have used our maps and satellite images, so today we're especially excited to launch &lt;a title="Google Maps Australia" href="http://maps.google.com.au/"&gt;Google Maps Australia&lt;/a&gt;. We've expanded service to include Australian business listings, driving directions, and support for Google Mobile Maps in Australia.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next time you're looking for an &lt;a title="address" href="http://maps.google.com.au/maps?q=1+Martin+Place,+Sydney+NSW+2000"&gt;address&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="tiger meat pie in Sydney" href="http://maps.google.com.au/maps?q=tiger+meat+pie+sydney"&gt;tiger meat pie in Sydney&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="cafes in Melbourne" href="http://maps.google.com.au/maps?q=cafes+melbourne"&gt;cafes in Melbourne&lt;/a&gt;, or how to &lt;a title="get to the beach" href="http://maps.google.com.au/maps?saddr=sydney&amp;daddr=bondi+beach"&gt;get to the beach&lt;/a&gt;, Google Maps can help you find the answer. If you're at your computer, go to &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com.au/"&gt;http://maps.google.com.au&lt;/a&gt; and start searching -- you can type addresses or business searches like [&lt;a title="cricket near melbourne" href="http://maps.google.com.au/maps?q=cricket+near+melbourne"&gt;cricket near melbourne&lt;/a&gt;] all into the same search box. If you want to access Google Maps on your mobile device, go to &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/gmm"&gt;http://www.google.com/gmm&lt;/a&gt; from your Java- enabled phone or Palm device to get started.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A good part of the Google Maps team works out of our Sydney R&amp;amp;D center, and we're really pleased to offer the full functionality of Google Maps to everyone down under. Please &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com.au/support/bin/request.py"&gt;let us know what you think&lt;/a&gt;!</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/02/google-maps-down-under.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/8279978029017418739'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/8279978029017418739'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-3740435828335157760</id><published>2007-02-16T10:44:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:31.919-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Online child safety initiatives</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Elliot Schrage, VP, Global Communications and Public Affairs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A big topic of discussion lately is the increasingly large influence media of all kinds can have in the lives of children and teens. Last week I participated in a &lt;a href="http://www.commonsensemedia.org/beyondprimetime/" title="conference"&gt;conference&lt;/a&gt; in New York about this important issue, sponsored by &lt;a href="http://www.commonsensemedia.org/"&gt;CommonSense Media&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.aspeninstitute.org/site/c.huLWJeMRKpH/b.2280181/k.3A10/Beyond_Primetime_Kids_and_the_Media.htm"&gt;The Aspen Institute&lt;/a&gt; together with several organizations that have a stake in child safety. (Here are &lt;a href="http://www.commonsensemedia.org/beyondprimetime/webcasts.php"&gt;videos of the speakers&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The conference organizers convened a panel of experts and executives to address the question "Does the Internet Change Everything?" I approached this question by suggesting a framework of four scenarios that characterize the online interactions of children and the content they encounter:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;When a child isn't actively seeking objectionable content online, and doesn't encounter any, no action is needed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;When a child isn't seeking objectionable content, but comes across it inadvertently, ISPs and other online services, like Google, and child safety organizations can provide tools and resources to help families effectively monitor their child's online interactions. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;When a child is actively seeking out objectionable content online and finds it, parents are primarily responsible for devising a solution. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;When a child isn't seeking out objectionable content, but someone deliberately forces such content on them, this amounts to exploitation -- and requires government involvement and cooperation by ISPs and other online services. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;So that you can see the types of things we're doing to promote safer online interactions, I've mapped some of Google's activities in this critical area of child safety online to these scenarios -- particularly 2 and 4, where we feel we can make the greatest difference.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In connection with the second scenario, we have invested in developing family safety technology and tools, including&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a title="SafeSearch" href="http://www.google.com/help/customize.html#safe"&gt;SafeSearch&lt;/a&gt;, a filter that uses advanced technology to block pornographic and explicit content from Google search results. We've also partnered with child safety organizations to educate families about ways to use the Internet and other types of media safely. These efforts include joining forces with CommonSense Media to provide &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a title="their movie reviews in Google search results" href="http://www.google.com/movies/reviews?cid=b86c7458ef13b529&amp;fq=the+queen"&gt;their movie reviews in Google search results&lt;/a&gt; to assist parents in identifying healthy content. We also work with organizations like &lt;a title="i-Safe" href="http://www.isafe.org/"&gt;i-Safe&lt;/a&gt;  and &lt;a title="iKeepSafe" href="http://www.ikeepsafe.org/iksc_kids/"&gt;iKeepSafe&lt;/a&gt; to provide online public service announcements that promote access to resources about Internet safety.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When the fourth scenario occurs, we work closely with law enforcement officials worldwide to identify, investigate and prosecute child pornography and exploitation. We remove child pornography immediately when we become aware of its presence on our search engine or content services, and report all instances of child pornography to law enforcement through the &lt;a title="National Center of Missing and Exploited Children, or NCMEC" href="http://www.missingkids.com/"&gt;National Center of Missing and Exploited Children, or NCMEC&lt;/a&gt;. We also respond to hundreds of child safety-related law enforcement requests each year, in addition to requests to preserve data related to these cases. Lastly, we donate hardware and software to improve NCMEC's ability to manage incoming reports of child exploitation and assist NCMEC in promoting its &lt;a title="CyberTipline" href="http://www.cybertipline.com/"&gt;CyberTipline&lt;/a&gt;, a resource for reporting cases of online child sexual exploitation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Keeping kids safe on the Internet is a huge task -- bigger than any single government, company or family. We're pleased to work with our industry partners, law enforcement and child safety advocates around the world (including the &lt;a href="http://www.iwf.org.uk/"&gt;Internet Watch Foundation&lt;/a&gt; in the UK and the Freiwillige Selbstkontrolle Multimedia (&lt;a href="http://www.fsm.de/"&gt;FSM&lt;/a&gt;) in Germany) to address this issue. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As we develop new initiatives in this critical arena, we'll keep you posted.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/02/online-child-safety-initiatives.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3740435828335157760'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/3740435828335157760'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-4693942147140005590</id><published>2007-01-30T15:29:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:24.554-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Google Mini turns 2</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Ryan Pollock, Product Marketing Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/enterprise/mini/"&gt;Our blue box&lt;/a&gt; is now two years old! To commemorate the Google Mini's second birthday, the enterprise team has developed an upgrade with greater security features and the ability to search across various business applications, all from the same search box. We've also made the Mini a better fit for public sites by integrating &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; and adding the ability to generate &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/siteoverview"&gt;Google Sitemaps&lt;/a&gt;. There's more about how the Mini is growing up on the &lt;a href="http://googleenterprise.blogspot.com/2007/01/little-blue-box-big-business-tech-for.html"&gt;Google Enterprise blog&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/01/google-mini-turns-2.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4693942147140005590'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/4693942147140005590'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-351827204880576189</id><published>2007-02-14T12:08:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:17.003-07:00</updated><title type='text'>From Gmail with &lt;3</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by David Murray, Associate Product Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gmail sign-ups are now open worldwide! No more waiting for someone to invite you—just create an account directly at &lt;a href="http://www.gmail.com/" title="www.gmail.com"&gt;www.gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. What better way to share the love with the people you care about than with &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/02/gmail-hearts-you.html"&gt;Gmail chat with &lt;3&lt;/a&gt;. And Gmail is available in &lt;a href="http://mail.google.com/support/bin/answer.py?answer=17091&amp;query=languages&amp;amp;topic=&amp;type=f&amp;amp;ctx=search%20%20"&gt;over 40 interface languages&lt;/a&gt; (though &lt;3 needs no translation).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But seriously folks, good relationships are built on good communication. There's no reason you should struggle to reach the ones you love, and Gmail helps you communicate fast and easily.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight:bold;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Update:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Just for the heck of it, we enlisted the help of an ensemble cast we think you'll enjoy. &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_YUugB4IUl4"&gt;Check out our 4-part video.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/02/from-gmail-with-3.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/351827204880576189'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/351827204880576189'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-4095260482186721826</id><published>2007-02-22T07:13:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:09.292-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Google Apps grows up</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Derek Parham, Lead Software Engineer, Google Apps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Back in 2005, Google Apps was conceived in a few lines of code, and then it was born in February 2006. Our team has had such a close relationship with it, you might understand how we have nurtured it as we would a child.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So first there was &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/02/big-mail-on-campus.html"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Gmail for your domain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; -- a limited service that helped organizations like San Jose City College offer personalized Gmail inboxes to all their users. As our little guy picked up new skills (Calendar, Talk, and Page Creator) it grew out of its old name and into &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/08/get-your-people-talking.html"&gt;Google Apps for Your Domain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A quick learner, by October Google Apps had perfected &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/10/get-your-people-talking-in-more.html"&gt;17 more languages&lt;/a&gt;, so we could help bring our communication tools all around the globe. Later in the fall, we improved our organizational skills with the &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/11/start-your-day-off-right.html"&gt;Start Page&lt;/a&gt;, which brought all the Apps together into a centralized place. Then it was time to start school. &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/10/score-one-for-sun-devils.html"&gt;Google Apps entered Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt; and stood out as one of those high achievers. Today, students and administrators at large universities like ASU and &lt;a href="http://communications.lakeheadu.ca/news/?display=news&amp;nid=310"&gt;Lakehead&lt;/a&gt; are raving about Apps  -- how it saves money and IT resources, plus make students lives easier with bigger spam-free mailboxes and a set of tools for working together.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now, I'm excited to tell you that our baby has finally graduated and is entering the business world. &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/a/enterprise"&gt;Google Apps Premier Edition&lt;/a&gt; is a new version designed to take on all the challenges presented by businesses with complex IT needs. For $50 per account per year, you get the whole Google Apps package plus many new business-oriented features, including access to our APIs and partner solutions (so it’s easy to integrate with existing systems), conference room scheduling for Calendar, 10GB of inbox storage, extended business hours phone support, and mobile access to your email on BlackBerry devices (just in case you can't get enough at the office).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Already, companies big and small, like Procter &amp;amp; Gamble, General Electric Corporation, Prudential, and SF Bay Pediatrics, are &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/a/help/intl/en/admins/customers.html"&gt;talking about&lt;/a&gt; how this new version of Google Apps makes it easy to offer low-cost communication and collaboration tools to all their employees so they can get on with what they do best.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Google Apps also won't forget its roots anytime soon. The &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/a"&gt;Standard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/a/edu"&gt;Education&lt;/a&gt; Editions will continue to be offered for free, and we'll keep working on all three flavors of Google Apps with the help of feedback from all of you. As a start, we’ve just integrated Google Docs &amp;amp; Spreadsheets in all three editions so that everyone can share and edit documents online. Since August, we’ve also added five more major features you've requested, including customized service URLs (mail.yourcompany.com) and domain registration for organizations that don’t yet have a custom domain. Our appearance has matured too, with updates to the administrator control panel that make it easier to setup and manage your services.</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/02/google-apps-grows-up.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4095260482186721826'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/4095260482186721826'></link><author><name>Karen</name></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-10861780.post-8193237435703073889</id><published>2007-01-30T09:30:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2007-05-15T20:46:02.255-07:00</updated><title type='text'>Our Seattle-Beijing collaboration</title><content type='html'>&lt;span class="byline-author"&gt;Posted by Feng Hu, Software Engineer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The one and only Dr. Kai-Fu Lee visited our Seattle office last week to speak with some 150 Googlers and guests about everything from future plans between our Beijing and Seattle offices to the way the Internet is used in China. Watch the video  [warning: 53 mins]--and consider joining our &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/jobs/seattlechina"&gt;pan-Pacific collaboration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;embed style="width: 400px; height: 326px;" id="VideoPlayback" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://video.google.com/googleplayer.swf?docId=1230747464670307641&amp;amp;hl=en" flashvars=""&gt; &lt;/embed&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Update:&lt;/span&gt; The video of the talk is now also available on &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=An+Inside+Look+at+Google+China+&amp;search=Search"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; [due to it's length the video is in six parts].</content><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/01/our-seattle-beijing-collaboration.html'></link><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://googleblog.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/8193237435703073889'></link><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/10861780/posts/default/8193237435703073889'></link><author><name>Molly Graham</name></author></entry></feed>